ratesupermarket.ca 2019-12-18

# Privacy Policy

## Our Privacy Pledge

RateSupermarket.ca owned and operated by Kanetix Ltd., believes in protecting the personal information that you provide us at www.ratesupermarket.ca. We have made safe computing and the protection of your privacy an important priority.

RateSupermarket.ca provides mortgage rates, credit card comparisons, banking rates and insurance quotes with minimal personal information. Except where mandated by the government and its regulatory bodies or the courts, the personal information that you share with us will not be shared with third parties without your prior consent.

## Security

Entering personal data on RateSupermarket.ca is not only easy but also safe. RateSupermarket.ca uses SSL (Secure Socket Layer) protocol, among the best Internet security software in the world, and DigiCert Inc. for securing the exchange of confidential data. This security technology encrypts the personal information that you send us (including things like names, addresses, emails and telephone numbers), so it cannot be read by anyone as it travels over the Internet. We will evaluate and adopt new security technology as it becomes available.

You can find out when the secure SSL connection is activated by looking for the key or padlock icon in the lower corner of your browser window. If the key becomes whole, or the padlock becomes closed, this indicates that the browser is now in "secure" mode.

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

If you have any questions about security on our website, you can email us at customercare(at)ratesupermarket.ca.

## Cookies

Cookies are small pieces of information stored on your hard drive. The only personal information that a cookie can contain is information supplied by the visitor and the cookies we use cannot read data off of our visitor hard disk or read cookie files created by other websites.

Cookie technology can save you time by eliminating the need to re-enter frequently requested information. Cookies also give us capability to understand how visitors use our site. We use this information to optimize our website and improve the visitor experience.

We use both session ID and persistent cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. If you choose to tick the box indicating you would like to be remembered, a persistent cookie is set so you dont have to reenter your login information more than once. If you later decide that you would no longer like to be remembered, the cookie will be removed when you log off. You can also remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser help file.

Please review your browser’s documentation, including the links below:

RateSupermarket.ca and its partners use cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users' movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. You can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level, but if you choose to disable cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on our website or service.

## Log files

As is true of most Web sites, we and our third party tracking-utility partner to gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.

We use this information, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track user movement around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

## Advertising

We partner with a third party to display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites, including ads pertaining to our clients' products. Our third party partners may use cookies or similar technologies in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising [click here.](https://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) Kanetix Ltd adheres to the Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada’s (the DAAC) self-regulatory principles for online behavioral advertising. You may also visit the[ Adchoices consumer opt out ](https://youradchoices.ca/Choices)page to learn more about interest based advertising and manage your ad preferences. Please note you will continue to receive generic ads.

## Collecting information

We gather and store data about online usage on a collective rather than individual basis. For example, like most websites, we gather aggregate information about the number of visitors that visit our website and the pages that they view, NOT what pages were viewed by each individual. We use this information to anticipate bottlenecks, to gauge the capacity of our servers, and to improve the overall management of our website.

## Collecting personal identifiable information

RateSupermarket.ca offers visitors the option to find rates for finanical products and personalized quotes and gathers personal information as part of these processes. Depending on the province, this may include obtaining your credit score from a credit reporting agency, or require you to provide details regarding your credit history. This information, along with the other details you enter will be used to provide you with a personalized offer and to determine the payment options that will be available to you.

Also, from time to time, RateSupermarket.ca requests and collects personal information from visitors via surveys, contests, "Refer-a-friend", promotional offers and Renewal Reminder services. Participation is completely voluntary (opt-in). Information requested has included your email address and that of the friend you are referring.

## Communication of personal Information

At various points on the RateSupermarket.ca website and when visitors contact RateSupermarket.ca, visitors may be asked if they consent to sharing their personal information with our affiliates and / or 3rd parties. If they agree, RateSupermarket.ca provides one or more affiliates and / or 3rd parties with their personal information for the purposes of either preparing or validating an insurance quote, requesting a call back from a mortgage professional or a GIC expert, confirming qualification for a promotional offer or providing marketing services as explicitly requested by the visitor.

## Email

RateSupermarket.ca will not accept transactions or instructions by Internet email messages. However, questions of a general nature or inquiries may be communicated by emailing our customer service team at customercare(at)ratesupermarket.ca.

By submitting your question, comment or suggestion online the information you provide becomes the property of RateSupermarket.ca. Where necessary, we may share the information you provide in your email with 3rd parties in order to address your question, comments or concerns. The content of your email may be used for any purpose and RateSupermarket.ca is free to use any idea contained in it for any purpose whatsoever, including, but not limited to, developing, manufacturing and marketing products using such information.

## Refer-a-friend

If you choose to use our referral service to refer a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. RateSupermarket.ca does not store this information.

## What is this personal information used for?

Our surveys are used to identify consumer insights or improve visitor satisfaction with our site. The Refer-a-friend service sends an email to a friend informing him/her about our site. With our Renewal Reminder service, visitors can elect to have an email reminder sent to them before their insurance policy or mortgage rate expires.

We will use the email address you provide us to send you copies of the insurance quotes and rate searches you have requested so you have a copy for your records.

## Policy holder information

If you apply online for insurance coverage or purchase a policy online through RateSupermarket.ca, additional information is needed to process your request. This information may include your first and last name, email address, and dwelling address; your telephone number, driver's licence number, vehicle identification number (if purchasing auto insurance), your current insurance company, employer name and credit card number or bank account information. We may also need to obtain your credit score from a credit reporting agency, or require you to provide details regarding your credit history. This information, along with the other details you have provided will only be used to fulfill services you specifically request. They will not be used for any other reason.

We forward this information to the insurance company who will be reviewing your application or underwriting your policy. If you agree to purchase a policy from the insurance company, it may use your personal information for the purpose of fulfilling the requested insurance transaction and for future contact in accordance with the terms and conditions of its own privacy policy.

## Framing

Some of our content is served on other pages using framing techniques to serve and provide our content and services on our partner sites while preserving the look and feel of their site. Please be aware that you are providing your personal information to RateSupermarket.ca for the services you are requesting and the use of your personal information is governed by this privacy policy.

Our select partners may also offer you the opportunity to opt-in to receiving information regarding their products and services. If you choose to receive these communications the information you provide is governed by their privacy policy.

## Service providers

In some cases, we use third parties to provide the mortgage rates and online quotes you receive on our site or to assist us in advertising our services to you. With respect to the quotes you get, the only information shared with the third party is the information required to provide you with an accurate quote. Depending on the type of quote you are seeking, this information may be comprised of one or more of the following: your age, gender, marital status, smoking status, driving, and insurance history. This information is only shared as necessary for the third party to provide you with an accurate quote. These third parties are prohibited from using your personal information for any other purpose.

## Testimonials

We post customer testimonials on our web site which may contain personal information. We do obtain the customer's consent via email prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial.

## How can you change your personal information?

Upon request RateSupermarket.com will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. You can change your username (email address) and password online in the Your RateSupermarket.ca Account section of the site or you can update your personal information by calling us at 1 (866) 462-4779 or writing to us at 360 Adelaide Street West, Suite 100, Toronto, Ontario, M5V 1R7. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel, delete or remove your account, or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services you can email us at customercare(at)ratesupermarket.ca. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

## For your protection

Your password is your private, secret entry code to your account information at RateSupermarket.ca. It is required when you first log in to view any promotional offers you may have signed up for. Your password keeps your account information private and secure and you can change it as many times as you like.

RateSupermarket.ca contains links to other websites. For example, you may find links to the suppliers featured in our comparison service or links to our affiliated brokerages. We do not exchange any information with these third-party sites if you click on them. If you do decide to click on one of these links, we encourage you to read the privacy statements of these linked sites as their policies may differ from ours.

## Opting out

We provide you the opportunity to opt-out of having your personal information used for certain purposes. For example, in some provinces we may ask your permission to obtain your credit score from a credit reporting agency, or ask you to provide details regarding your credit history. This information, along with the other details you enter will be used to provide you with a personalized offer and to determine the payment options that will be available to you. You can opt to not provide us with this permission and still get quotes.

Another example in how you can opt out involves our newsletter or renewal reminder service. If you sign up for these optional services we automatically send you a confirmation email specifying the services you requested. From these confirmation emails, you can opt-out of both of these services at any time by replying and indicating your preference to be removed from our lists. You can also opt-out by emailing us at customercare(at)ratesupermarket.ca, following the unsubscribe instructions in the email communications you receive, calling us at 1 (866) 462-4779 or by writing to us at 360 Adelaide Street West, Suite 100, Toronto, Ontario, M5V 1R7.

You will be notified when your personal information is collected by any third party that is not one of our service providers, so you can make an informed choice as to whether or not to share your information with that party.

## Public Forums

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, email us at customercare(at)ratesupermarket.ca. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

## Social Media Features and Widgets

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

## Supplementation of personal information

We may obtain information about you from third parties when you provide us with your driver's licence such as name and date of birth. We use this information in order to make it easier for you to use our site and services.

## Notification of changes

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email or by means of a notice on our homepage prior to the change becoming effective.

## Legal disclaimer

We reserve the right to disclose your personal information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our website or in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

In the event RateSupermarket.ca goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personal information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via prominent notice on our Web site for 30 days of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information.

## If you have any concerns

We are committed to providing excellent service to you. However, if you have a concern or complaint, please contact us, because we are also committed to working with you to achieve a resolution and following through to a successful conclusion as quickly as possible. In most cases, complaints are resolved simply by discussing it with us. You should be able to get swift results by calling one of our customer associates at 1 (866) 462-4779, emailing us at customercare(at)ratesupermarket.ca or by writing to us at: RATESUPERMARKET.CA 360 Adelaide Street West, Suite 100, Toronto ON, M5V 1R7

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at [https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request ](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request).
